Juhwan Lee

Portland, OR • Cell: 360-593-6736 • ljh1230vvv@gmail.com • juhwan@pdx.edu https://www.linkedin.com/in/iuhwan-lee/ • https://aithub.com/iuroc95 • https://iuroc95.aithub.io/

ABOUT

Enthusiastic software engineer with extensive technical experience in software testing and full-stack web development in a professional team environment. Familiar with data structures, object-oriented programming, systems programming, algorithms, and relational databases. Successfully work in teams and self-directed settings with the ability to quickly learn and master new technologies.

EDUCATION

PORTLAND STATE UNIVERSITY

Portland, Oregon

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Expected Graduation: Mar 2023

- Overall GPA: 3.55 / 4.00
- Activities and societies: Software Engineering Capstone Team Lead
- Academic honors: President's List (Winter 2022), Dean's List (Spring 2022), International Achievement Scholarships (\$12,000)
- Relevant courses: Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Systems Programming, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Algorithms and Complexity, Relational Databases, Web Development

SKILLS

Technologies: C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Node.js, Linux, Vim, VScode, Git Languages: Native in Korean, Fluent in English

EXPERIENCE

FASOO Seoul, South Korea

Software Engineer Intern

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Worked as part of a four-member team under the Wrapsody Development team for the internship project called Wrapsody eCo Workspace
- Designed and implemented a new collaborative workspace, where users can freely share their opinions, within Wrapsody eCo by integrating a real-time open-source collaborative text editor called Etherpad
- Presented Wrapsody eCo Workspace in front of the CEO, team leaders, and senior developers on the last day of the internship

MEDIAZEN Seoul, South Korea Jun 2021 - Sep 2021

Software Engineer Intern

- Suggested new application ideas for STT, TTS, NLU, and Computer Vision in front of the team leader and senior developers on the
- first week of the internship Created 1000 test scenarios for the advancement of ART (Automatic Recognition Test), a software testing automation tool
- Responsible for software testing of the Volkswagen Voice Control System and reporting test results to the project manager when a new version is released

REPUBLIC OF KOREA NAVY

Gyeryong, South Korea Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

Petty Officer Second Class, Administrative Clerk

- In charge of reporting the personnel status of the FF-956 to the fleet, flotilla, and squadron
- Assisted in administrative work in the secretary's office of the vice chief of naval operations

PROJECTS

WALKTOBER (Position: Team Lead)

Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

- Develop a cross-platform fitness challenge app called Walktober that is integrated with built-in iOS and Android fitness tracking systems by using TypeScript, Node.js, React, Ionic Framework, and Firebase
- Users can create an account, log in, log out, create or join a team, track their steps, interact with the participants, view the leaderboard for the event and for their team, and view event-wide announcements

WRAPSODY ECO WORKSPACE (Position: Team Member)

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Designed and implemented a new collaborative workspace, where users can freely share their opinions, within Wrapsody eCo by integrating a real-time open-source collaborative text editor called Etherpad
- Wrapsody eCo users can now freely share their opinions with their team members without having to move to the different platform

FULL STACK REALTIME CHAT MESSAGING APP (Individual Project)

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

- Created a custom chat application using JavaScript, Node.js, React, and Stream by following JavaScript Mastery Tutorial
- This chat application includes direct and group chats, emojis & reactions, built-in gif support, the ability to edit & delete messages, specialized commands, and much more